Guide to the Hayes Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Biographical Documentation, 1898-1994; Series II
  - Paul G. Hayes
    - Death certificate, obituary notices, 1994 Mar (Box 29, Folder 388)
    - Death - Correspondence letters of condolence after death (addressed to LAHA), 1994 Mar (Box 29, Folder 389)
    - Duke St. Methodist Church (Lancaster, PA), 1907-1966, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 390)
    - Employment (early opportunities), 1911-1920 (Box 29, Folder 391)
    - European trips, 1926, 1932-1933 (Box 29, Folder 392)
    - Excelsior United Methodist Church (Excelsior, MN), 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 393)
    - Fiftieth Wedding Anniversary celebration (invitation), 1972 Jun 25 (Box 29, Folder 394)
    - First Methodist Episcopal Church (Lancaster, PA), 1904-1920 (Box 29, Folder 395)
    - Franklin Marshall Academy, 1906, 1911-1913, 1938, 1979-1980 (Box 29, Folder 396)
    - Franklin Marshall College - letter of acceptance, YMCA SVM materials, class papers, announcement of PGH as winner of State Prize in WCTU College Essay Contest, 1913-1916 (Box 29, Folder 397)
    - Franklin Marshall College - graduation materials, Marshall Oration (PGH as speaker at Commencement), 1917 (Box 30, Folder 398)
    - Franklin Marshall College - post-graduation materials; alumni materials, 1917, 1919,1942-1989 (Box 30, Folder 399)
    - Franklin Marshall College - Catalogue, 1917-1918 (Box 30, Folder 400)
    - Franklin Marshall College - Student Weekly (selected issues), 1915-1917 (Box 30, Folder 401)
    - Fremont (NH) United Congregational Church, 1920 May-1921 Mar (Box 30, Folder 402)
    - General Board of Global Ministries, U.M.C., 1989 Jun-Nov (Box 30, Folder 403)
    - Greenwood Cemetery (Allentown, PA)(re. burial site grave markers) (Box 30, Folder 403)
    - Hamline United Methodist Church (St. Paul, MN) (PGH's tenure as Associate Minister, 1970 Nov 12 - 1977 Jun 12) correspondence, reports, directories, 1971-1980, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 404)
    - Hamline United Methodist Churchphotos of new members, 1968-1977 (Box 30, Folder 405)
    - Hartford Seminary Foundation, Kennedy School of Missions (HWH-1921, PGH-1928), 1927-1928, 1934, 1950, 1970, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 406)
    - Hayes, Mary Zwally (PGH's first wife: married 1917 Sep 8; died 1918 Oct 13), 1917-1918 (Box 30, Folder 407)
    - "Heroes" (persons admired by PGH) (incl. Martin Luther King, Jr., Frank C. Laubach, Pope John XXIII, Methodist Bishop D. Stanley Coors, Norman Thomas, Pierre Teilhard de Chardin), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 408)
    - Hu Shih, "My Credo Its Evolution", reprinted from The Forum, 1931 Jan-Feb (Box 31, Folder 409)
    - Kuling American School - "Lushan Memories", compiled by Paul Sheretz, 1985 Sep (Box 31, Folder 410)
    - Lake Harriet United Methodist Church (Minneapolis, MN) Adult Bible Class, 1967-1979 (Box 31, Folder 411-412)
    - Lake Harriet United Methodist - Church Reports by PGH, 1961-1989 (Box 31, Folder 413)
    - Lake Harriet United Methodist Church - Pastor-Parish Relations, 1961-1970 (Box 31, Folder 414)
    - Lancaster, PA [note by PGH: See also page in Album #1], 1898,1946, 1969,1977, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 415)
    - Linden Methodist Episcopal Church (Malden, MA), 1918-1919, 1940,1960, 1969, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 416)
    - The Linguist (published by the students of the Nanking Language School, Univ. of Nanking), 1921-1923 (Box 31, Folder 417)
    - Liu, I Hsin, 1956, 1971, 1973, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 418)
    - McCabe Methodist Church (Bismarck, ND), 1941-1949, 1959, 1976, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 419-420)
    - Memoirs of PGH (actual ms. in Series III): biographical materials, 1978-1979, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 421-422)
    - Memoirs of PGH - notes on ms. by EHL, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 423)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, Board of Foreign Missions, 1911-1921 (Box 32, Folder 424)
    - Methodist Ministry - PGH's 50th 60th anniversary celebrations, 1967, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 425)
    - Midwest China Study Resource Center, Oral History Archives Project: correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 426)
    - Midwest China Study Resource Center, Oral History Archives Project: transcript of PGH [copyright restrictions detailed in preface], 1977 Mar (Box 32, Folder 427)
    - Minnesota, 1936-1982 (Box 32, Folder 428)
    - Miscellaneous [incl. chronologies and biographical notes by PGH and EHL], 1908-1990 (Box 33, Folder 429)
    - Nanking Language School, 1921-1922 (Box 33, Folder 430)
    - New York Hartford, 1926-1928 (Box 33, Folder 431)
    - Newspaper clippings on Hayes family, 1899-1935, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 432)
    - North Dakota, 1917-1948 (Box 33, Folder 433)
    - Phi Beta Kappa (election of PGH), 1917,1972, 1980, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 434)
    - Philadelphia Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, 1916-1917, 1920 (Box 33, Folder 435)
    - Prohibition Temperance, 1914-1916 (Box 33, Folder 436)
    - Public schools attended, 1897-1910 (Box 33, Folder 437)
    - Roberts, Oral - Evangelistic Association University, 1976-1980, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 438-439)
    - Resurrection (writings on), 1934, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 440)
    - Rochester, MN, 1950-1984 (Box 34, Folder 441)
    - Ross Street Church, 1916-1973 (Box 34, Folder 442)
    - Shelton College (Ringwood, NJ), 1956, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 443)
    - Simpson United Methodist Church (Minneapolis, MN): miscellaneous, 1937-1982 (Box 34, Folder 444)
    - Simpson United Methodist Church - Simpson Summons, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 445)
    - Social and Economic Relations Board, Minnesota Annual Conference, 1953, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 446)
    - Southeast District (MN) (PGH as District Superintendent of the Methodist Church), 1955-1961 (Box 34, Folder 447)
    - Student Volunteers, 1914-1915 (Box 34, Folder 448)
    - Travel Around the World, 1978, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 449)
    - Travels in the U.S.A., 1955-1979 (Box 34, Folder 450)
    - Travels - Record of journey from Shanghai to New York (duplicated in PGH's Journal), 1935 May 29 - Aug 19 (Box 35, Folder 451)
    - Union Missionary Training Institute, 1909-1918 (Box 35, Folder 452)
    - Union Theological Seminary, 1926-1927, 1938-1979, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 453-454)
    - Universal Military Training, ca.1940s-1950s (Box 35, Folder 455)
    - Walker Methodist Residence and Health Services, Inc. (Minneapolis, MN) [incl. re. PGH HWH's admission], 1983, 1986-1989, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 456-458)
    - Water Street Mission, 1909-1919, 1950-1985 (Box 35, Folder 459-461)
    - Water Street Mission - "Messenger" (monthly newsletter), 1947-1979 (Box 36, Folder 462-463)
    - Watkins Home, 1970-1983 (Box 36, Folder 464)
    - Windsor Locks, CT: Grace Methodist Episcopal Church, 1928 (Box 36, Folder 465)
    - Windsor Locks, CT: re. tornado, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 465)
    - Wuhu, Anhwei, China (memorabilia, correspondence, report on Wuhu Methodist Conference - 1931 Apr 2), 1920s-1940s (Box 36, Folder 466)
    - Yale Divinity School Library, China Records Project, 1970-1979 (Box 36, Folder 467)
  - Helen Wolf Hayes
    - Materials re. departure and missionary service in China, 1920-1921 (Box 37, Folder 468)
    - Midwest China Oral History transcript, 1977 Apr 27, May 4 16 (Box 37, Folder 469)
    - "The Life and Ministry of Helen Hayes: Pages from the Memoirs of Her Husband", 1985 Oct 17 (Box 37, Folder 470)
    - Death - Death certificate materials re. death, 1988 Jul (Box 37, Folder 471)
    - Death - Letters of condolence re. death (addressed to PGH EHL), memorial contributions, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 472)
    - Misc. [incl. chronology biographical notes), n.d. (Box 37, Folder 472A)
  - Elsie Hayes Landstrom and Norman Landstrom
    - Curriculum Vitae, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 473-474)
    - NL's Obituary, EHL's correspondence re. NL's death, 1989 Nov (Box 37, Folder 475)
- Writings, 1907-1991; Series III
  This series contains the writings of the following members of the Hayes Family:
  Articles, newsletters, sermons and memoirs of Paul G. Hayes (1907-1983)
  Memoirs of Helen Wolf Hayes (1946-1981)
  Booklength manuscripts of Elsie Hayes Landstrom (1981-1991)
  - Paul G. Hayes
    - Articles for Chinese Recorder (manuscript version), 1929-1932 (Box 38, Folder 476)
    - Southeast District Newsletters, 1955-1961 (Box 38, Folder 477)
    - Sermons - #1-150, preached at Water St. Mission, 1907-1916;#151-262, preached at Ross St. Methodist Episcopal Church, 1916-1917;#473-497, preached in China, 1st term, 1921-1926;#498-549, preached on Furlough, 1926-1928; #550-609, preached in China, 2nd term, 1928-1935, 1907-1917, 1921-1935 (Box 39A, Folder 478)
    - Sermons - #2604-2669, preached at Lake Harriet Methodist Church, 1961 Jul 2-1965 May 16; #2670-2726, preached at Lake Harriet Methodist Church, 1965 Aug 1-1970 Jun 21; #2727-2788, preached during "2nd Retirement", 1970 Jun 28-1977 Jun 12; #2789-2817, preached during "3rd Retirement", 1977 Jun 19-1983, 1961-1983 (Box 39B, Folder 479)
    - Sermons - "Make Love Your Aim", a biographical sermon preached by PGH at Lake Harriet Methodist Church on the 50th anniversary of his ministry, 1967 Apr 16; "Christ's Greater Works", preached at Lake Harriet United Methodist Church, 1982 Feb 21, 1967, 1982 (Box 39B, Folder 480)
    - Memoirs (edited by Elsie Hayes Landstrom), 1981 (Box 41, Folder 484)
    - Vol. I: Lancaster to China, 1890-1926 (Box 41, Folder 484)
    - Vol. II: Furlough Years, 1926-1928 (Box 41, Folder 485)
    - Vol. III: Second Term in China, 1928-1935 (Box 41, Folder 486)
    - Vol. IV: Return to America, 1935-1941 (Box 42, Folder 487)
    - Vol. V: Eight Years in Bismarck, 1941-1949 (Box 42, Folder 488)
    - Vol. VI-A: Six Years in Albert Lea, 1949-1955 (Box 42, Folder 489)
    - Vol. VI-B: Six Years in Albert Lea, 1949-1955 (Box 43, Folder 490)
    - Vol. VII: Six Years in Rochester, 1955-1961 (Box 43, Folder 491)
    - Vol. VIII-A: Nine Years at Lake Harriet, 1961-1970 (Box 43, Folder 492)
    - Vol. VIII-B: Nine Years at Lake Harriet, 1961-1970 (Box 44, Folder 493)
    - Vol. IX: Seven Years at Hamline, 1970-1977 and Final Retirement, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 494)
    - Complete draft, unbound (Box 45, Folder 495)
  - Helen Wolf Hayes
    - Memoirs: "Memories of China, 1921-1935", written 1946, 1953, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 481-482)
    - Memoirs: Early years and Wolf family, written ca. 1981 (Box 40, Folder 483)
  - Elsie Hayes Landstrom
    - "With Kindness in His Hands: The Story of My Father, Paul G. Hayes" (2 vols.), 1982 (Box 46, Folder 496)
    - "The Welcoming Pine: Journal of a Return", 1983 (Box 47, Folder 497)
    - "Closing the Circle", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 498)
    - "Story of Wuhu Hospital" "Report of Jing Li Tour" (1 bound vol.), 1981 1982 (Box 48, Folder 499)
    - "Hyla Doc" (1st draft ms.; published in 1991 as Hyla Doc: Surgeon in China Through War and Revolution, 1924-1949, ed. by EHL) (Box 48, Folder 500)
    - Various notes, correspondence, drafts re. writings, 1985, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 501)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series IV
  This series contains materials relating to and/or collected by the following members of the Hayes Family:
  Paul G. Hayes (1888-1989, n.d.)
  Helen Wolf Hayes (1921-1970, n.d.)
  Zachariah T. Hayes (father of PGH) (1889, 1893)
  Elsie Hayes Landstrom (1932-1989, n.d.)
  - Paul G. Hayes
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 502)
    - Art Instruction Industrial Drawing Workbooks for Elementary Schools, 1888, 1892 (Box 49, Folder 503)
    - Guest books, 1922-1934, 1936,1949, 1972,1955, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 504)
    - Library list, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 505)
    - Notebooks - Notes, itinerary: Shanghai to New York, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 506)
    - Notes in Chinese, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 506)
    - Notes on Minnesota Pastors' Conference, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 506)
    - Collected programs - Sermons of Dr. J. Wilbur Chapman of the Chapman-Alexander Evangelistic Mission, Brooklyn, NY, Feb 1-28; Tercentenary Celebration of the King James Version of the Bible, Carnegie Hall, NY, Apr 25, 1911 (Box 49, Folder 507)
    - Wesley College - PGH's Honorary Doctor of Divinity Degree, 1949 Jun 10 (Box 49, Folder 508)
    - Financial records - Travel expense account: Shanghai to NY, 1935 (Box 50, Folder 509)
    - Cash books, 1950-1983 (Box 50, Folder 509)
    - Record books of financial transactions, 1970 Jul-1972 May, 1983 Sep-1985 Nov, 1985 Nov-1988 Oct (Box 50, Folder 510-511)
    - Financial statements, 1986,1988, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 512-513)
    - Record book of contributions (alphabetically arranged by organization), ca.1950s-1980s (Box 50, Folder 514)
    - Tithing accounts, 1980, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 515)
    - Power of Attorney Papers (PGH HWH), 1987 Apr 15 (Box 50, Folder 516)
    - Glass slides (incl. slides of China, Calvary Methodist Church announcements, Christmas carols), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 517)
    - Issue of Water Street Rescue Mission newsletter article: "Laying the Foundation: Paul G. Hayes 1907-1916" documents PGH's work at the Mission, 2005 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Bound volume of Chinese language material with enclosures (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Helen Wolf Hayes
    - Diploma from Hartford Seminary Foundation, Kennedy School of Missions, 1921 May 25 (Box 52, Folder 518)
    - Notes class paper on Chinese literature while studying under Dr. Hodous, American Sinologue, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 519)
    - Class notes, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 520)
    - Class notes on Christian doctrine, Chinese language (Box 52, Folder 521)
    - Notes for China talks, 1944, 1970, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 522)
  - Zachariah T. Hayes (father of PGH)
    - History of the First Methodist Episcopal Church of Lancaster, PA, 1807-1893 (Box 52, Folder 523)
    - Directory of the Philadelphia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, 1889 (Box 52, Folder 523)
    - Elsie Hayes Landstrom
    - Collected research material re. Wuhu, China, 1932-1989, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 524)
    - Ms. by Ella C. Shaw on opening of Nanking Mission, given to EHL by Lucile Libby, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 525)
- Photograph Albums, 1890-1949; Series V
  Nine photograph albums are chronologically arranged.
  - Album 1: "558 N. Queen, Lancaster, PA; First Methodist Church; Water Street Mission; Franklin Marshall Coll.; Ross Street Methodist", 1890-1917 (Box 53)
  - Album 2: "Ross Street Methodist; Marriage to Mary Zwally; B.U. School of Theology; Linden Malden Methodist; Fremont Congregational", 1917-1921
  - Album 3: "Drew and Cross Country; SS Korea Maru; Helen; Nanking Language School; Peking; Wedding; Kuling; Wuhu; Elsie Rhoda", 1921-1923 (Box 54)
  - Album 4: "Years at Ichishan Wuhu; S.S. Saarbruecken Ports; Shanghai to Genoa; Genoa to London; RMS Majestic to NYC", 1923-1925
  - Album 5: "Union; Columbia Univ.; Clinton; Windsor Locks; Hartford Seminary; Hartford to Vancouver; SS Empress of Canada", 1925-1928 (Box 55)
  - Album 6: "Chinkiang Ichishan Wuhu; Summers on Kuling; Kiangsi; Lindberg; Stamm; Smith; Lois Anne born 11/8/31; Farewell after 14 years", 1928-1935
  - Album 7: "SS Saarbrucken: Shanghai, Suez, Bremen; SS Europa to New York; Simpson Meth., Mpls.; Columbus; Washington", 1935-1936 (Box 56)
  - Album 8: "Calvary Mpls and Fire; Mother Wolf; Rollin and Barbara Wolf; Summer trips to East; NY World's Fair 1940", 1936-1941
  - Album 9: "McCabe Meth. Bismark, ND; Four summers in Mpls, Yellowstone, Glacier; Elsie married; Cheney; Sister Rhoda on trips", 1941-1949 (Box 57)